Dolores Miller ILGWU Memorabilia 6036/091 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Dolores Miller ILGWU Memorabilia
1971-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Miller, Dolores
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
6036/091 MB
6.42 cubic feet
6.4 linear ft.
Memorabilia.
8595063
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 08, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, May 08, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6036/091 AV: Dolores Miller ILGWU Audio-Visual Materials 6036/091 P: Dolores Miller ILGWU Photographs 6036/091 PUBS: Dolores Miller ILGWU and Other Publications
Miller, Dolores; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
8595063
- Blue denim satchel/travel bag (Box 1, Folder 1)
- White canvas bag - "42nd ILGWU Convention, June, 1995, Miami Beach, Florida" (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Green velour satchel (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Knitted sweater - white with red stripes and blue piping - lettering "Union made ILGWU AFL-CIO, made in U.S.A." (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Knitted sweater - white with red and blue has union label knitted on the front and "International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union on the back of the sweater (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Denim material with the Union Label printed on it (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bright colored (flowers) pieces of material all with the Union Label stamped on it (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Pillow cover - with red fringe - made from Union Label material, with an insert in the center that is had stitched to show the Union Label and writing "Midwest Region District Council 2, Dolores Miller Business Manager" (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bandana - Blue-gold-red-white colored cloth with a geometric design, stamped with the Union Label (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Cotton Jacket - made out of ILGWU material with bright flowers (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Valet bag (paper) from the Fontainebleau, Miami Beach; 2 plastic 'shopping bags' - from the ILGWU (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bumper Sticker - "Keep America Working" paper placemat from the Chez Bon Bon (Box 2, Folder 1)
- White t-shirt - Union Label on front left lapel, ILGWU on the back (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Blue cotton t-shirt -- "On the MOVE" on the front (Box 2, Folder 3)
- White cotton t-shirt - "Liberty & Union ILGWU" in a circle on front with picture of Statue of Liberty's face (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Black t-shirt - "UNITE and Fight" with ILGWU on the back (Box 2, Folder 5)
- White t-shirt - Union label shown on the front (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Light blue t-shirt - "On the MOVE." (Box 2, Folder 7)
- ILGWU bingo cards (Box 3, Folder 1)
- ILGWU visor (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Local 120 sign (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Charles and Dolores Miller, Delegate badges (assorted) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous - Buttons, Sticker, Business Card (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Assorted buttons (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Assorted Buttons (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Assorted buttons, name tag (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Assorted Buttons (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Assorted Buttons (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Assorted Buttons (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Assorted Buttons (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Assorted Buttons (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Jewelry, Pins, key chains (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Charm Bracelets (ILGWU) (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Convention Entertainment (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Convention Receipts (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 1971 + 1974 Convention Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 19)
- 1971 + 1974 Convention Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 20)
- 1971 + 1974 Convention Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 21)
- 1971 + 1974 Convention Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 22)
- 1971 + 1974 Convention Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Luggage tags (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Plastic Rain Hats (Box 3, Folder 25)
- ILGWU sewing kits (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Rulers, pocket protectors, note pad (Box 3, Folder 27)
- UNITE - watch (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous ILGWU Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Ad sketches/examples (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Political bumper stickers -- Dawn Clark - NETSCH Governor (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Miscellaneous Certificates (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous Awards (Box 3, Folder 34)